Emmanuel Akinsiku

 ② 28 Ogunfunwa Street, Ogijo b/stop, Sagamu, Nigeria

 ☑ akinsnuel@gmail.com

 ③ 08133946674

https://github.com/Olly-E ## 29/04/1996 https://nuelportfolio.netlify.app/

Education

2017 – 2019	Electrical Electronics Engineering HND, Federal Polytechnic Ede, Osun State
2014 – 2016	Electrical Electronics Engineering ND, Federal Polytechnic Ede, Osun State
2009 – 2013	SSCE, Godswill comprehensive school, Ogijo Ogun State

Profile

Front-end developer with 3 years of experience designing and building responsive web design and mobile apps in the financial industry. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 80% with improved code and design.

Skills

HTML html-5	• • • •	css css3 and scss	••••
Javascript ECMA	• • • •	React Js React and React Native	• • • • •
Material Ui	• • • •	Figma	••••
Framer Motion	• • • • •	Git and Github	• • • • •
Tailwind css	• • • • •	Photoshop	
Gatsby	• • • • •	Styled Components	• • • • •
Next Js	• • • •	Typescript	• • • •

Professional Experience

01/2017 – 06/2017 Sagamu, Nigeria **Undergraduate Intern,** *Lafarge Plc*

• Built a Staff interaction Website and anonymous complaint Plattform

2020 - 2021

Frontend Engineer, *Clinical*

Built a web app aiding hospital transactions and patient onboarding

- Translated Figma designs into efficient codes
- awesome user experience and interactions
- integrated various payment and database Api
- designed and implemented user and admin dashboards
- Collaborated with the UX/UI design teams to improve the website and applications, increasing conversion rates by 35%
- Presented findings in a clear and concise manner to key decision-makers
- Daily maintenance of code, debugging issues and solving clients' problems

2022 Lagos, Nigeria

Frontend Engineer, Paybuymax Tech

Building a fintech app with crypto transaction perks.

- Translated Figma designs and work flow
- Converted designs into reusable, efficient and easy to read code.
- designed intriguing user experience and interactions
- integrated various payment APIs
- built a speed website preceeding the main Launch

Projects

2021	
2021	

Estimate-app

An app that records list of stuff and price associated and gives the calculated value of the balance remaining from the overall money spent

2021

Contact app

built a contact app with React utilizing react router and browser local storage

2021

Clinical, built a mini clinic Web app that helps with transactions and clients data base and history records

A clinic Web app that does more than record patience medical history, also gives them reminder, aids transactions and recommendations

Dashboard, built a customer dashboard with framer motion and sass built a dashboard with standout animation

2021

Stylio

built a fashion and body treatment website with amazing user interaction and eye catching designs

2022

Coin Screamer

A crypto price and description app that shows the price market and progressive chart of multiply crypto currencies

2022

Portfolio Website

A portfolio website showing qualifications and experience with information about the user and various means of direct contacts

2021 - 2021

A Blog site, *embarked on a blog project with more than just the regular elements.* built a blog app with react utilising the MERN stack

01/2022

Paybuymax, built a complete Webapp for a start up crypto based organization

- Translated Figma ui designs into efficient and readable codes
- · Built an admin and user dashboard
- implemented various payment APIs and user accounts APIs
- implemented a career page